<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<databaseChangeLog
        xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog"
        xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
        xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
 http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-3.1.xsd">

    <changeSet id="ENG-8200-01" author="mdaly">
        <comment>Remove AGG reflex text from 45-54 templates (CS3). The ids for affected templates are:
            "45-54 CGG repeats": 26
            ">Two CGG alleles detected, one allele intermediate (45-54)": 30
            "Two alleles intermediate (45-54)": 35
        </comment>
        <sql>
            UPDATE `prodlims`.`HorizonDiseaseResultTemplate`
            SET `clinicalDetails` = 'An intermediate size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[0])!"cgg1"} CGG repeat allele and a normal size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[1])!"cgg2"} allele were detected in the FMR1 genes. This individual is not at increased risk to have a child with Fragile X Syndrome. In some cases, intermediate size repeat alleles can expand to a premutation (carrier status) in future generations.'
            WHERE `id` = 26;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`HorizonDiseaseResultTemplate`
            SET `clinicalDetails` = 'An intermediate sized ${(results[0].cggRepeats[0])!"cgg1"} CGG repeat allele and a normal sized ${(results[0].cggRepeats[1])!"cgg2"} CGG repeat allele were detected in the FMR1 gene. An additional allele in the normal range with ${(results[0].cggRepeats[2])!"cgg3"} CGG repeats was also detected. The presence of three alleles in this individual''s sample may be due to X chromosome aneuploidy, a duplication on the X chromosome, a somatic change in one of the alleles, or a PCR artifact. Karyotype and/or chromosomal microarray may be considered to clarify these results. This individual is not at increased risk to have a child with Fragile X Syndrome. In some cases, intermediate size repeat alleles can expand to a premutation (carrier status) in future generations.'
            WHERE `id` = 30;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`HorizonDiseaseResultTemplate`
            SET `clinicalDetails` = 'One intermediate size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[0])!"cgg1"} and one intermediate size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[1])!"cgg2"} CGG repeat alleles were detected in the FMR1 gene. This individual is not at increased risk to have a child with Fragile X Syndrome. In some cases, intermediate size repeat alleles can expand to a premutation (carrier status) in future generations.'
            WHERE `id` = 35;
        </sql>

        <rollback>
            UPDATE `prodlims`.`HorizonDiseaseResultTemplate`
            SET `clinicalDetails` = 'An intermediate size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[0])!"cgg1"} CGG repeat allele and a normal size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[1])!"cgg2"} allele were detected in the FMR1 genes. This individual is not at increased risk to have a child with Fragile X Syndrome. In some cases, intermediate size repeat alleles can expand to a premutation (carrier status) in future generations. AGG testing through Asuragen Laboratories will be performed and a separate report will be sent. This report will refine the chance for expansion of the CGG repeat tract.'
            WHERE `id` = 26;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`HorizonDiseaseResultTemplate`
            SET `clinicalDetails` = 'An intermediate sized ${(results[0].cggRepeats[0])!"cgg1"} CGG repeat allele and a normal sized ${(results[0].cggRepeats[1])!"cgg2"} CGG repeat allele were detected in the FMR1 gene. An additional allele in the normal range with ${(results[0].cggRepeats[2])!"cgg3"} CGG repeats was also detected. The presence of three alleles in this individual''s sample may be due to X chromosome aneuploidy, a duplication on the X chromosome, a somatic change in one of the alleles, or a PCR artifact. Karyotype and/or chromosomal microarray may be considered to clarify these results. This individual is not at increased risk to have a child with Fragile X Syndrome. In some cases, intermediate size repeat alleles can expand to a premutation (carrier status) in future generations. AGG testing through Asuragen Laboratories will be performed and a separate report will be sent. This report will refine the chance for expansion of the CGG repeat tract.'
            WHERE `id` = 30;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`HorizonDiseaseResultTemplate`
            SET `clinicalDetails` = 'One intermediate size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[0])!"cgg1"} and one intermediate size ${(results[0].cggRepeats[1])!"cgg2"} CGG repeat alleles were detected in the FMR1 gene. This individual is not at increased risk to have a child with Fragile X Syndrome. In some cases, intermediate size repeat alleles can expand to a premutation (carrier status) in future generations. AGG testing through Asuragen Laboratories will be performed and a separate report will be sent. This report will refine the chance for expansion of the CGG repeat tract.'
            WHERE `id` = 35;
        </rollback>
    </changeSet>

    <changeSet id="ENG-8200-02" author="mdaly">
        <comment>Remove AGG reflex text from 45-54 templates for CS2.
        </comment>
        <sql>
            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 0;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`horizondiseasetemplate`
            SET `variant` = REPLACE(`variant`, ' AGG testing through Asuragen Laboratories will be performed and a separate report will be sent. This report will refine the chance for expansion of the CGG repeat tract.', '')
            WHERE `gene` = 'FMR1' AND `templatecode` IN (
            '45-54 CGG repeats',
            '>2 CGG alleles detected, one allele intermediate (45-54)',
            'Two alleles intermediate (45-54)'
            );

            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 1;
        </sql>

        <rollback>
            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 0;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`horizondiseasetemplate`
            SET `variant` = CONCAT(`variant`, ' AGG testing through Asuragen Laboratories will be performed and a separate report will be sent. This report will refine the chance for expansion of the CGG repeat tract.')
            WHERE `gene` = 'FMR1' AND `templatecode` IN (
            '45-54 CGG repeats',
            '>2 CGG alleles detected, one allele intermediate (45-54)',
            'Two alleles intermediate (45-54)'
            );

            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 1;
        </rollback>
    </changeSet>

    <changeSet id="ENG-8200-03" author="mdaly">
        <comment>There are duplicate CS2 templates for intermediate results. Edit the text so users don't use them.
            Removing is more complicated because of FKs with HorizonTemplateVariable and HorizonReportDiseaseResult
        </comment>
        <sql>
            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 0;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`horizondiseasetemplate` SET
            `templatecode` = CONCAT('DO NOT USE. ', `templatecode`)
            WHERE
            `gene` = 'FMR1' AND
            `templateCode` IN (
            '1 CGG allele detected, intermediate (45-54)',
            '1 CGG allele detected, premutation (55-90 repeats)',
            '1 CGG allele detected, premutation (91-200 repeats)');

            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 1;
        </sql>
        <rollback>
            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 0;

            UPDATE `prodlims`.`horizondiseasetemplate` SET
            `templatecode` = REPLACE(`templatecode`, 'DO NOT USE. ', '')
            WHERE
            `gene` = 'FMR1' AND
            `templateCode` IN (
            'DO NOT USE. 1 CGG allele detected, intermediate (45-54)',
            'DO NOT USE. 1 CGG allele detected, premutation (55-90 repeats)',
            'DO NOT USE. 1 CGG allele detected, premutation (91-200 repeats)');

            SET SQL_SAFE_UPDATES = 1;
        </rollback>
    </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>